{
    "N4L26VQuiz": [
        { "question": "check, take a look at", "kanji_question": "見ます、診ます", "answer": "みます" },
        { "question": "look for, search", "kanji_question": "探します、捜します", "answer": "さがします" },
        { "question": "be late [for an appointment, etc.]", "kanji_question": "「時間に」遅れます", "answer": "「じかんに」おくれます" },
        { "question": "be in time [for an appointment, etc.]", "kanji_question": "「時間に」間に合います", "answer": "「じかんに」まにあいます" },
        { "question": "do", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "やります" },
        { "question": "pick up", "kanji_question": "拾います", "answer": "ひろいます" },
        { "question": "contact, get in touch with", "kanji_question": "連絡します", "answer": "れんらくします" },
        { "question": "feel well", "kanji_question": "気分がいい", "answer": "きぶんがいい" },
        { "question": "feel ill", "kanji_question": "気分が悪い", "answer": "きぶんがわるい" },
        { "question": "athletic meeting, sports day", "kanji_question": "運動会", "answer": "うんどうかい" },
        { "question": "Bon Festival dance", "kanji_question": "盆踊り", "answer": "ぼんおどり" },
        { "question": "flea market", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "フリーマーケット" },
        { "question": "place", "kanji_question": "場所", "answer": "ばしょ" },
        { "question": "volunteer", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ボランティア" },
        { "question": "wallet, purse", "kanji_question": "財布", "answer": "さいふ" },
        { "question": "garbage, rubbish, dust", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ごみ" },
        { "question": "the Diet Building", "kanji_question": "国会議事堂", "answer": "こっかいぎじどう" },
        { "question": "weekday", "kanji_question": "平日", "answer": "へいじつ" },
        { "question": "~ dialect", "kanji_question": "～弁", "answer": "～べん" },
        { "question": "next time, another time", "kanji_question": "今度", "answer": "こんど" },
        { "question": "pretty, very", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ずいぶん" },
        { "question": "directly", "kanji_question": "直接", "answer": "ちょくせつ" },
        { "question": "any time", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いつでも" },
        { "question": "anywhere", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どこでも" },
        { "question": "anybody", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "だれでも" },
        { "question": "anything", "kanji_question": "何でも", "answer": "なんでも" },
        { "question": "~ like this", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こんな～" },
        { "question": "~ like that (near the listener)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そんな～" },
        { "question": "~ like that (far from both the speaker and the listener)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あんな～" },
        { "question": "[boxes] be put in order, tidy up", "kanji_question": "「荷物が」片づきます", "answer": "「にもつが」かたづきます" },
        { "question": "put out [the trash, the rubbish]", "kanji_question": "「ごみを」出します", "answer": "「ごみを」だします" },
        { "question": "burnable rubbish", "kanji_question": "燃えるごみ", "answer": "もえるごみ" },
        { "question": "place where something is put", "kanji_question": "置き場", "answer": "おきば" },
        { "question": "side", "kanji_question": "横", "answer": "よこ" },
        { "question": "bottle", "kanji_question": "瓶", "answer": "びん" },
        { "question": "can", "kanji_question": "缶", "answer": "かん" },
        { "question": "gas", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ガス" },
        { "question": "~ company", "kanji_question": "～会社", "answer": "～がいしゃ" },
        { "question": "space, universe", "kanji_question": "宇宙", "answer": "うちゅう" },
        { "question": "Mr. ~/Ms. ~ (respectful equivalent of ～さん)", "kanji_question": "～様", "answer": "～さま" },
        { "question": "spaceship", "kanji_question": "宇宙船", "answer": "うちゅうせん" },
        { "question": "be afraid of", "kanji_question": "怖い", "answer": "こわい" },
        { "question": "spaceship, space station", "kanji_question": "宇宙ステーション", "answer": "うちゅうステーション" },
        { "question": "be different", "kanji_question": "違います", "answer": "ちがいます" },
        { "question": "astronaut", "kanji_question": "宇宙飛行士", "answer": "うちゅうひこうし" }
    ],
    "N4L27VQuiz": [
        { "question": "keep (a pet), raise (an animal)", "kanji_question": "飼います", "answer": "かいます" },
        { "question": "run, drive [along a road]", "kanji_question": "「道を」走ります", "answer": "「みちを」はしります" },
        { "question": "[a mountain] can be seen", "kanji_question": "「山が」見えます", "answer": "「やまが」みえます" },
        { "question": "[a sound] can be heard", "kanji_question": "「音が」聞こえます", "answer": "「おとが」きこえます" },
        { "question": "[a road] be made, be completed", "kanji_question": "「道が」できます", "answer": "「みちが」できます" },
        { "question": "set up [a class], open, hold", "kanji_question": "「教室を」開きます", "answer": "「きょうしつを」ひらきます" },
        { "question": "worried, anxious", "kanji_question": "心配", "answer": "しんぱい" },
        { "question": "pet", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ペット" },
        { "question": "bird", "kanji_question": "鳥", "answer": "とり" },
        { "question": "voice", "kanji_question": "声", "answer": "こえ" },
        { "question": "wave", "kanji_question": "波", "answer": "なみ" },
        { "question": "fireworks", "kanji_question": "花火", "answer": "はなび" },
        { "question": "tool, instrument, equipment", "kanji_question": "道具", "answer": "どうぐ" },
        { "question": "(dry) cleaning, laundry", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "クリーニング" },
        { "question": "house, home", "kanji_question": "家", "answer": "いえ" },
        { "question": "condominium, apartment house", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "マンション" },
        { "question": "kitchen", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "キッチン" },
        { "question": "~ class", "kanji_question": "～教室", "answer": "～きょうしつ" },
        { "question": "party room", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パーティールーム" },
        { "question": "person (respectful equivalent of ひと)", "kanji_question": "方", "answer": "かた" },
        { "question": "after ~ (duration of time)", "kanji_question": "～後", "answer": "～ご" },
        { "question": "only ~ (used with negatives)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～しか" },
        { "question": "other", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ほかの" },
        { "question": "clearly", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "はっきり" },
        { "question": "furniture", "kanji_question": "家具", "answer": "かぐ" },
        { "question": "bookshelf, bookcase", "kanji_question": "本棚", "answer": "ほんだな" },
        { "question": "someday, sometime, one day", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いつか" },
        { "question": "build", "kanji_question": "建てます", "answer": "たてます" },
        { "question": "marvelous, wonderful", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すばらしい" },
        { "question": "children", "kanji_question": "子どもたち", "answer": "こどもたち" },
        { "question": "like very much", "kanji_question": "大好き", "answer": "だいすき" },
        { "question": "hero, heroine", "kanji_question": "主人公", "answer": "しゅじんこう" },
        { "question": "shape", "kanji_question": "形", "answer": "かたち" },
        { "question": "fantastic, mysterious", "kanji_question": "不思議", "answer": "ふしぎ" },
        { "question": "pocket", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ポケット" },
        { "question": "for example", "kanji_question": "例えば", "answer": "たとえば" },
        { "question": "attach, put on", "kanji_question": "付けます", "answer": "つけます" },
        { "question": "freely", "kanji_question": "自由に", "answer": "じゆうに" },
        { "question": "sky", "kanji_question": "空", "answer": "そら" },
        { "question": "fly", "kanji_question": "飛びます", "answer": "とびます" },
        { "question": "old days, ancient times", "kanji_question": "昔", "answer": "むかし" },
        { "question": "oneself", "kanji_question": "自分", "answer": "じぶん" },
        { "question": "future", "kanji_question": "将来", "answer": "しょうらい" }
    ],
    "N4L28VQuiz": [
        { "question": "[bread] sell, be sold", "kanji_question": "「パンが」売れます", "answer": "「パンが」うれます" },
        { "question": "dance", "kanji_question": "踊ります", "answer": "おどります" },
        { "question": "chew, bite", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かみます" },
        { "question": "choose", "kanji_question": "選びます", "answer": "えらびます" },
        { "question": "go to and from [university]", "kanji_question": "「大学に」通います", "answer": "「だいがくに」かよいます" },
        { "question": "take a memo", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "メモします" },
        { "question": "serious", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まじめ" },
        { "question": "earnest", "kanji_question": "熱心", "answer": "ねっしん" },
        { "question": "great, admirable", "kanji_question": "偉い", "answer": "えらい" },
        { "question": "proper, just right", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ちょうどいい" },
        { "question": "scenery, view", "kanji_question": "景色", "answer": "けしき" },
        { "question": "hair salon", "kanji_question": "美容院", "answer": "びよういん" },
        { "question": "kitchen", "kanji_question": "台所", "answer": "だいどころ" },
        { "question": "experience", "kanji_question": "経験", "answer": "けいけん" },
        { "question": "power", "kanji_question": "力", "answer": "ちから" },
        { "question": "popularity", "kanji_question": "人気", "answer": "にんき" },
        { "question": "form, shape", "kanji_question": "形", "answer": "かたち" },
        { "question": "colour", "kanji_question": "色", "answer": "いろ" },
        { "question": "taste", "kanji_question": "味", "answer": "あじ" },
        { "question": "chewing gum", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ガム" },
        { "question": "goods", "kanji_question": "品物", "answer": "しなもの" },
        { "question": "price", "kanji_question": "値段", "answer": "ねだん" },
        { "question": "salary", "kanji_question": "給料", "answer": "きゅうりょう" },
        { "question": "bonus", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ボーナス" },
        { "question": "(computer) game", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ゲーム" },
        { "question": "programme", "kanji_question": "番組", "answer": "ばんぐみ" },
        { "question": "drama", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ドラマ" },
        { "question": "singer", "kanji_question": "歌手", "answer": "かしゅ" },
        { "question": "novel", "kanji_question": "小説", "answer": "しょうせつ" },
        { "question": "novelist", "kanji_question": "小説家", "answer": "しょうせつか" },
        { "question": "~er, ~ist, etc. (e.g. painter, novelist)", "kanji_question": "～家", "answer": "～か" },
        { "question": "~ machine", "kanji_question": "～機", "answer": "～き" },
        { "question": "(my) son", "kanji_question": "息子", "answer": "むすこ" },
        { "question": "(someone else's) son", "kanji_question": "息子さん", "answer": "むすこさん" },
        { "question": "(my) daughter", "kanji_question": "娘", "answer": "むすめ" },
        { "question": "(someone else's) daughter", "kanji_question": "娘さん", "answer": "むすめさん" },
        { "question": "oneself", "kanji_question": "自分", "answer": "じぶん" },
        { "question": "future", "kanji_question": "将来", "answer": "しょうらい" },
        { "question": "a little while", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "しばらく" },
        { "question": "usually, mostly", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "たいてい" },
        { "question": "in addition", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "それに" },
        { "question": "and so", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "それで" },
        { "question": "I have a [small] favour to ask.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「ちょうと」おねがいがあるんですが。" },
        { "question": "as a matter of fact", "kanji_question": "実は", "answer": "じつは" },
        { "question": "conversation", "kanji_question": "会話", "answer": "かいわ" },
        { "question": "well, let me see, hmmm...", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うーん" },
        { "question": "notice", "kanji_question": "お知らせ", "answer": "おしらせ" },
        { "question": "participate, join, attend", "kanji_question": "参加します", "answer": "さんかします" },
        { "question": "date", "kanji_question": "日にち", "answer": "ひにち" },
        { "question": "Saturday", "kanji_question": "土", "answer": "ど" },
        { "question": "gymnasium", "kanji_question": "体育館", "answer": "たいいくかん" },
        { "question": "free of charge", "kanji_question": "無料", "answer": "むりょう" },
        { "question": "invite, ask someone to join", "kanji_question": "誘います", "answer": "さそいます" },
        { "question": "event", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "イベント" }
    ],
    "N4L29VQuiz": [
        { "question": "(a door) open", "kanji_question": "開きます", "answer": "あきます" },
        { "question": "(a door) close, shut", "kanji_question": "閉まります", "answer": "しまります" },
        { "question": "(a light) come on, be turned on", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "つきます" },
        { "question": "(a light) go off", "kanji_question": "消えます", "answer": "きえます" },
        { "question": "(a chair) break", "kanji_question": "壊れます", "answer": "こわれます" },
        { "question": "(a glass) break, smash", "kanji_question": "割れます", "answer": "われます" },
        { "question": "(a tree) break, snap", "kanji_question": "折れます", "answer": "おれます" },
        { "question": "(paper) tear", "kanji_question": "破れます", "answer": "やぶれます" },
        { "question": "(clothes) get dirty", "kanji_question": "汚れます", "answer": "よごれます" },
        { "question": "(a pocket) be attached", "kanji_question": "付きます", "answer": "つきます" },
        { "question": "(a button) be undone", "kanji_question": "外れます", "answer": "はずれます" },
        { "question": "(a car) stop, park", "kanji_question": "止まります", "answer": "とまります" },
        { "question": "make a mistake", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まちがえます" },
        { "question": "drop, lose", "kanji_question": "落とします", "answer": "おとします" },
        { "question": "be locked", "kanji_question": "掛かります", "answer": "かかります" },
        { "question": "wipe", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ふきます" },
        { "question": "change", "kanji_question": "取り替えます", "answer": "とりかえます" },
        { "question": "put (things) in order, tidy up", "kanji_question": "片づけます", "answer": "かたづけます" },
        { "question": "plate, dish", "kanji_question": "「お」皿", "answer": "「お」さら" },
        { "question": "(rice) bowl", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「お」ちゃわん" },
        { "question": "glass (vessel)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "コップ" },
        { "question": "glass (material)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ガラス" },
        { "question": "bag", "kanji_question": "袋", "answer": "ふくろ" },
        { "question": "document, papers", "kanji_question": "書類", "answer": "しょるい" },
        { "question": "branch, twig", "kanji_question": "枝", "answer": "えだ" },
        { "question": "station attendant", "kanji_question": "駅員", "answer": "えきいん" },
        { "question": "police box", "kanji_question": "交番", "answer": "こうばん" },
        { "question": "speech", "kanji_question": "駅員", "answer": "スピーチ" },
        { "question": "reply, answer", "kanji_question": "返事", "answer": "へんじ" },
        { "question": "After you./Go ahead, please.", "kanji_question": "お先にどうぞ。", "answer": "おさきにどうぞ。" },
        { "question": "the train which has just left", "kanji_question": "今の電車", "answer": "いまのでんしゃ" },
        { "question": "things left behind, lost property", "kanji_question": "忘れ物", "answer": "わすれもの" },
        { "question": "about this (big)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "このくらい" },
        { "question": "~ side", "kanji_question": "～側", "answer": "～がわ" }, 
        { "question": "pocket", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ポケット" },
        { "question": "around ~, ~ about", "kanji_question": "～辺", "answer": "～へん" },
        { "question": "I don't remember.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おぼえていません。" },
        { "question": "overhead rack", "kanji_question": "網棚", "answer": "あみだな" },
        { "question": "I'm pretty sure", "kanji_question": "確か", "answer": "たしか" },
        { "question": "[Oh] that's great!/Thank goodness! (used to express a feeling of relief)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「ああ」よかった。" },
        { "question": "earthquake", "kanji_question": "地震", "answer": "じしん" },
        { "question": "wall", "kanji_question": "壁", "answer": "かべ" },
        { "question": "hands (of a clock)", "kanji_question": "針", "answer": "はり" },
        { "question": "point", "kanji_question": "指します", "answer": "さします" },
        { "question": "the area in front of a station", "kanji_question": "駅前", "answer": "えきまえ" },
        { "question": "fall down", "kanji_question": "倒れます", "answer": "たおれます" },
        { "question": "west", "kanji_question": "西", "answer": "にし" },
        { "question": "direction of ~", "kanji_question": "～の方", "answer": "～のほう" },
        { "question": "burn", "kanji_question": "燃えます", "answer": "もえます" },
        { "question": "reporter", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "レポーター" }
    ],
    "N4L30VQuiz": [
        { "question": "put up, post, paste", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "はります" },
        { "question": "hang", "kanji_question": "掛けます", "answer": "かけます" },
        { "question": "display, decorate", "kanji_question": "飾ります", "answer": "かざります" },
        { "question": "arrange, line up", "kanji_question": "並べます", "answer": "ならべます" },
        { "question": "plant", "kanji_question": "植えます", "answer": "うえます" },
        { "question": "return, put ~ back", "kanji_question": "戻します", "answer": "もどします" },
        { "question": "put ~ together, put ~ in shape, sum up", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まとめます" },
        { "question": "put (things) away", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "しまいます" },
        { "question": "decide", "kanji_question": "決めます", "answer": "きめます" },
        { "question": "prepare one's lesson", "kanji_question": "予習します", "answer": "よしゅうします" },
        { "question": "review one's lesson", "kanji_question": "復習します", "answer": "ふくしゅうします" },
        { "question": "leave things as they are", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そのままにします" },
        { "question": "class", "kanji_question": "授業", "answer": "じゅぎょう" },
        { "question": "lecture", "kanji_question": "講義", "answer": "こうぎ" },
        { "question": "meeting", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ミーティング" },
        { "question": "plan, schedule", "kanji_question": "予定", "answer": "よてい" },
        { "question": "notice", "kanji_question": "お知らせ", "answer": "おしらせ" },
        { "question": "guidebook", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ガイドブック" },
        { "question": "calendar", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カレンダー" },
        { "question": "poster", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ポスター" },
        { "question": "schedule", "kanji_question": "予定表", "answer": "よていひょう" },
        { "question": "trash can, dustbin", "kanji_question": "ごみ箱", "answer": "ごみばこ" },
        { "question": "doll", "kanji_question": "人形", "answer": "にんぎょう" },
        { "question": "vase", "kanji_question": "花瓶", "answer": "かびん" },
        { "question": "mirror", "kanji_question": "鏡", "answer": "かがみ" },
        { "question": "drawer", "kanji_question": "引き出し", "answer": "ひきだし" },
        { "question": "front door, porch, entrance hall", "kanji_question": "玄関", "answer": "げんかん" },
        { "question": "corridor, hallway", "kanji_question": "廊下", "answer": "ろうか" },
        { "question": "wall", "kanji_question": "壁", "answer": "かべ" },
        { "question": "pond", "kanji_question": "池", "answer": "いけ" },
        { "question": "original place", "kanji_question": "元の所", "answer": "もとのところ" },
        { "question": "round, around", "kanji_question": "周り", "answer": "まわり" },
        { "question": "centre", "kanji_question": "真ん中", "answer": "まんなか" },
        { "question": "corner", "kanji_question": "隅", "answer": "すみ" },
        { "question": "still", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まだ" },
        { "question": "rucksack", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "リュック" },
        { "question": "emergency kit", "kanji_question": "非常袋", "answer": "ひじょうぶくろ" },
        { "question": "emergency", "kanji_question": "非常時", "answer": "ひじょうじ" },
        { "question": "live", "kanji_question": "生活します", "answer": "せいかつします" },
        { "question": "torch, flashlight", "kanji_question": "懐中電灯", "answer": "かいちゅうでんとう" },
        { "question": "~, ~, and so on", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～とか、～とか" },
        { "question": "round", "kanji_question": "丸い", "answer": "まるい" },
        { "question": "one ~, a certain ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ある～" },
        { "question": "dream", "kanji_question": "夢を見ます", "answer": "ゆめをみます" },
        { "question": "glad, happy", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うれしい" },
        { "question": "hateful, disagreeable", "kanji_question": "嫌", "answer": "いや" },
        { "question": "and, then", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すると" },
        { "question": "wake up", "kanji_question": "目が覚めます", "answer": "めがさめます" }
    ],
    "N4L31VQuiz": [
        { "question": "continue", "kanji_question": "続けます", "answer": "つづけます" },
        { "question": "find", "kanji_question": "見つけます", "answer": "みつけます" },
        { "question": "take (a holiday)", "kanji_question": "取ります", "answer": "とります" },
        { "question": "take (an examination)", "kanji_question": "受けます", "answer": "うけます" },
        { "question": "apply for, enter for", "kanji_question": "申し込みます", "answer": "もうしこみます" },
        { "question": "take a break, take a rest", "kanji_question": "休憩します", "answer": "きゅうけいします" },
        { "question": "consecutive holidays", "kanji_question": "連休", "answer": "れんきゅう" },
        { "question": "essay, composition", "kanji_question": "作文", "answer": "さくぶん" },
        { "question": "announcement, presentation", "kanji_question": "発表", "answer": "はっぴょう" },
        { "question": "exhibition", "kanji_question": "展覧会", "answer": "てんらんかい" },
        { "question": "wedding ceremony", "kanji_question": "結婚式", "answer": "けっこんしき" },
        { "question": "funeral", "kanji_question": "「お」葬式", "answer": "「お」そうしき" },
        { "question": "ceremony", "kanji_question": "式", "answer": "しき" },
        { "question": "head office", "kanji_question": "本社", "answer": "ほんしゃ" },
        { "question": "branch office", "kanji_question": "支店", "answer": "してん" },
        { "question": "church", "kanji_question": "教会", "answer": "きょうかい" },
        { "question": "graduate school", "kanji_question": "大学院", "answer": "だいがくいん" },
        { "question": "zoo", "kanji_question": "動物園", "answer": "どうぶつえん" },
        { "question": "hot spring, spa", "kanji_question": "温泉", "answer": "おんせん" },
        { "question": "return", "kanji_question": "帰り", "answer": "かえり" },
        { "question": "(someone else's) child", "kanji_question": "お子さん", "answer": "おこさん" },
        { "question": "(train number, typhoon number, etc.)", "kanji_question": "～号", "answer": "～ごう" },
        { "question": "place toward ~, direction of ~", "kanji_question": "～の方", "answer": "～のほう" },
        { "question": "the whole time", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ずっと" },
        { "question": "remain, be left, stay behind", "kanji_question": "残ります", "answer": "のこります" },
        { "question": "entrance examination", "kanji_question": "入学試験", "answer": "にゅうがくしけん" },
        { "question": "per month", "kanji_question": "月に", "answer": "つきに" },
        { "question": "village", "kanji_question": "村", "answer": "むら" },
        { "question": "graduate", "kanji_question": "卒業します", "answer": "そつぎょうします" },
        { "question": "movie theater, cinema", "kanji_question": "映画館", "answer": "えいがかん" },
        { "question": "hateful, disagreeable", "kanji_question": "嫌", "answer": "いや" },
        { "question": "sky", "kanji_question": "空", "answer": "そら" },
        { "question": "close", "kanji_question": "閉じます", "answer": "とじます" },
        { "question": "city", "kanji_question": "都会", "answer": "とかい" },
        { "question": "children", "kanji_question": "子どもたち", "answer": "こどもたち" },
        { "question": "freely", "kanji_question": "自由に", "answer": "じゆうに" }
    ],
    "N4L32VQuiz": [
        { "question": "take exercise", "kanji_question": "運動します", "answer": "うんどうします" },
        { "question": "succeed", "kanji_question": "成功します", "answer": "せいこうします" },
        { "question": "fail (an examination)", "kanji_question": "失敗します", "answer": "しっぱいします" },
        { "question": "pass (an examination)", "kanji_question": "合格します", "answer": "ごうかくします" },
        { "question": "(rain) stop", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "やみます" },
        { "question": "clear up", "kanji_question": "晴れ明日", "answer": "はれます" },
        { "question": "get cloudy", "kanji_question": "曇ります", "answer": "くもります" },
        { "question": "(high temperature) continue", "kanji_question": "続きます", "answer": "つづきます" },
        { "question": "catch (a cold)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ひきます" },
        { "question": "cool", "kanji_question": "冷やします", "answer": "ひやします" },
        { "question": "(a road) get crowded", "kanji_question": "込みます", "answer": "こみます" },
        { "question": "(a road) get less crowded", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すきます" },
        { "question": "participate (in the match)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "でます" },
        { "question": "attend (a party)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "でます" },
        { "question": "overdo things", "kanji_question": "無理をします", "answer": "むりをします" },
        { "question": "enough, sufficient", "kanji_question": "十分", "answer": "じゅうぶん" },
        { "question": "strange, funny", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おかしい" },
        { "question": "noisy", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うるさい" },
        { "question": "doctor", "kanji_question": "先生", "answer": "せんせい" },
        { "question": "burning", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "やけど" },
        { "question": "injury", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "けが" },
        { "question": "cough", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "せき" },
        { "question": "influenza", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "インフルエンザ" },
        { "question": "sky", "kanji_question": "空", "answer": "そら" },
        { "question": "sun", "kanji_question": "太陽", "answer": "たいよう" },
        { "question": "star", "kanji_question": "星", "answer": "ほし" },
        { "question": "wind", "kanji_question": "風", "answer": "かぜ" },
        { "question": "east", "kanji_question": "東", "answer": "ひがし" },
        { "question": "west", "kanji_question": "西", "answer": "にし" },
        { "question": "south", "kanji_question": "南", "answer": "みなみ" },
        { "question": "north", "kanji_question": "北", "answer": "きた" },
        { "question": "international ~", "kanji_question": "国際～", "answer": "こくさい～" },
        { "question": "faucet, tap, water supply", "kanji_question": "水道", "answer": "すいどう" },
        { "question": "engine", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "エンジン" },
        { "question": "team", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "チーム" },
        { "question": "this evening", "kanji_question": "今夜", "answer": "こんや" },
        { "question": "late afternoon", "kanji_question": "夕方", "answer": "ゆうがた" },
        { "question": "a time in the past, before", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まえ" },
        { "question": "late (time)", "kanji_question": "遅く", "answer": "おそく" },
        { "question": "like this", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こんなに" },
        { "question": "like that (concerning a matter not related to the speaker or the listener)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そんなに" },
        { "question": "that much, like that (concerning a matter not related to the speaker or the listener)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あんなに" },
        { "question": "Europe", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ヨーロッパ" },
        { "question": "vigor", "kanji_question": "元気", "answer": "げんき" },
        { "question": "stomach", "kanji_question": "胃", "answer": "い" },
        { "question": "stress", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ストレス" },
        { "question": "I'm sorry to hear that.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "それはいけませんね。" },
        { "question": "horoscope", "kanji_question": "星占い", "answer": "ほしうらない" },
        { "question": "Taurus", "kanji_question": "牡牛座", "answer": "おうしざ" },
        { "question": "overworking", "kanji_question": "働きすぎ", "answer": "はたらきすぎ" },
        { "question": "be in trouble, have a problem", "kanji_question": "困ります", "answer": "こまります" },
        { "question": "lottery", "kanji_question": "宝くじ", "answer": "たからくじ" },
        { "question": "win (a lottery)", "kanji_question": "当たります", "answer": "あたります" },
        { "question": "health", "kanji_question": "健康", "answer": "けんこう" },
        { "question": "romantic love", "kanji_question": "恋愛", "answer": "れんあい" },
        { "question": "sweetheart, boyfriend, girlfriend", "kanji_question": "恋人", "answer": "こいびと" },
        { "question": "something lucky", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ラッキーアイテム" },
        { "question": "stone", "kanji_question": "石", "answer": "いし" }
    ],
    "N4L33VQuiz": [
        { "question": "run away", "kanji_question": "逃げます", "answer": "にげます" },
        { "question": "make a noise", "kanji_question": "騒ぎます", "answer": "さわぎます" },
        { "question": "give up", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あきらめます" },
        { "question": "throw", "kanji_question": "投げます", "answer": "なげます" },
        { "question": "keep, follow, obey", "kanji_question": "守ります", "answer": "まもります" },
        { "question": "(a ceremony) begin, start", "kanji_question": "始まります", "answer": "はじまります" },
        { "question": "attend (a meeting)", "kanji_question": "出席します", "answer": "しゅっせきします" },
        { "question": "convey", "kanji_question": "伝えます", "answer": "つたえます" },
        { "question": "be careful (of the cars)", "kanji_question": "注意します", "answer": "ちゅういします" },
        { "question": "be away (from one's desk)", "kanji_question": "外します", "answer": "はずします" },
        { "question": "come back, return", "kanji_question": "戻ります", "answer": "もどります" },
        { "question": "have (a telephone call)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あります" },
        { "question": "recycle", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "リサイクルします" },
        { "question": "no good, not permitted, impossible", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "だめ" },
        { "question": "same", "kanji_question": "同じ", "answer": "おなじ" },
        { "question": "police (station)", "kanji_question": "警察", "answer": "けいさつ" },
        { "question": "seat", "kanji_question": "席", "answer": "せき" },
        { "question": "mark, symbol", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "マーク" },
        { "question": "ball", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ボール" },
        { "question": "deadline", "kanji_question": "締め切り", "answer": "しめきり" },
        { "question": "regulation, rule", "kanji_question": "規則", "answer": "きそく" },
        { "question": "Danger", "kanji_question": "危険", "answer": "きけん" },
        { "question": "Do Not Use", "kanji_question": "使用禁止", "answer": "しようきんし" },
        { "question": "Keep Out", "kanji_question": "立入禁止", "answer": "たちいりきんし" },
        { "question": "Go Slow", "kanji_question": "徐行", "answer": "じょこう" },
        { "question": "entrance", "kanji_question": "入口", "answer": "いりぐち" },
        { "question": "exit", "kanji_question": "出口", "answer": "でぐち" },
        { "question": "emergency exit", "kanji_question": "非常口", "answer": "ひじょうぐち" },
        { "question": "Free of Charge", "kanji_question": "無料", "answer": "むりょう" },
        { "question": "Discount", "kanji_question": "割引", "answer": "わりびき" },
        { "question": "All You Can Drink", "kanji_question": "飲み放題", "answer": "のみほうだい" },
        { "question": "In Use", "kanji_question": "使用中", "answer": "しようちゅう" },
        { "question": "Applications Wanted", "kanji_question": "募集中", "answer": "ぼしゅうちゅう" },
        { "question": "~ing", "kanji_question": "～中", "answer": "～ちゅう" },
        { "question": "what kind of~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どういう～" },
        { "question": "however~, even if~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いくら「～ても」" },
        { "question": "(not) any longer (used with negatives)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もう" },
        { "question": "~left", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あと～" },
        { "question": "about~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～ほど" },
        { "question": "parking violation", "kanji_question": "駐車違反", "answer": "ちゅうしゃいはん" },
        { "question": "fine", "kanji_question": "罰金", "answer": "ばっきん" },
        { "question": "earthquake", "kanji_question": "じしん", "answer": "じしん" },
        { "question": "happen", "kanji_question": "起きます", "answer": "おきます" },
        { "question": "help each other", "kanji_question": "助け合います", "answer": "たすけあいます" },
        { "question": "originally", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もともと" },
        { "question": "sad", "kanji_question": "悲しい", "answer": "かなしい" },
        { "question": "more", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もっと" },
        { "question": "greeting, address", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あいさつ" },
        { "question": "the other person", "kanji_question": "相手", "answer": "あいて" },
        { "question": "feeling", "kanji_question": "気持ち", "answer": "きもち" }
    ],
    "N4L34VQuiz": [
        { "question": "brush (one's teeth), polish", "kanji_question": "磨きます", "answer": "みがきます" },
        { "question": "assemble", "kanji_question": "組み立てます", "answer": "くみたてます" },
        { "question": "bend, fold, break, snap", "kanji_question": "折ります", "answer": "おります" },
        { "question": "notice, become aware of (things left behind)", "kanji_question": "気がつきます", "answer": "きがつきます" },
        { "question": "put (in soy sauce)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "つけます" },
        { "question": "(a key) be found", "kanji_question": "見つかります", "answer": "みつかります" },
        { "question": "ask a question", "kanji_question": "質問します", "answer": "しつもんします" },
        { "question": "put up (an umbrella)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "さします" },
        { "question": "sports club", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スポーツクラブ" },
        { "question": "castle", "kanji_question": "「お」城", "answer": "「お」しろ" },
        { "question": "explanatory pamphlet, instruction book", "kanji_question": "説明書", "answer": "せつめいしょ" },
        { "question": "figure, drawing", "kanji_question": "図", "answer": "ず" },
        { "question": "line", "kanji_question": "線", "answer": "せん" },
        { "question": "arrow (sign)", "kanji_question": "矢印", "answer": "やじるし" },
        { "question": "black (noun)", "kanji_question": "黒", "answer": "くろ" },
        { "question": "white (noun)", "kanji_question": "白", "answer": "しろ" },
        { "question": "red (noun)", "kanji_question": "赤", "answer": "あか" },
        { "question": "blue (noun)", "kanji_question": "青", "answer": "あお" },
        { "question": "navy blue, dark blue (noun)", "kanji_question": "紺", "answer": "こん" },
        { "question": "yellow (noun)", "kanji_question": "黄色", "answer": "きいろ" },
        { "question": "brown (noun)", "kanji_question": "茶色", "answer": "ちゃいろ" },
        { "question": "soya, soy sauce", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "しょうゆ" },
        { "question": "sauce, Worcestershire sauce", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ソース" },
        { "question": "visitor, guest, customer, client", "kanji_question": "お客「さん」", "answer": "おきゃく「さん」" },
        { "question": "~or~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～か～" },
        { "question": "last night", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ゆうべ" },
        { "question": "a short while ago", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "さっき" },
        { "question": "tea ceremony", "kanji_question": "茶道", "answer": "さどう" },
        { "question": "make (green) tea (at a tea ceremony)", "kanji_question": "お茶をたてます", "answer": "おちゃをたてます" },
        { "question": "first, ahead", "kanji_question": "先に", "answer": "さきに" },
        { "question": "place on, load onto", "kanji_question": "載せます", "answer": "のせます" },
        { "question": "Is this all right?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "これでいいですか。" },
        { "question": "How is it?", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いかがですか。" },
        { "question": "bitter", "kanji_question": "苦い", "answer": "にがい" },
        { "question": "a bowl of cooked rice with chicken and egg", "kanji_question": "親子どんぶり", "answer": "おやこどんぶり" },
        { "question": "material, ingredient", "kanji_question": "材料", "answer": "ざいりょう" },
        { "question": "portion for~ (used for indicating quantity)", "kanji_question": "～分", "answer": "～ぶん" },
        { "question": "~gramme", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～グラム" },
        { "question": "(counter for small objects)", "kanji_question": "～個", "answer": "～こ" },
        { "question": "onion", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "たまねぎ" },
        { "question": "one fourth", "kanji_question": "４分の１", "answer": "４ぶんの１" },
        { "question": "seasoning, flavouring", "kanji_question": "調味料", "answer": "ちょうみりょう" },
        { "question": "in right size", "kanji_question": "適当な大きさに", "answer": "てきとうなおおきさに" },
        { "question": "pan, pot", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "なべ" },
        { "question": "fire, heating", "kanji_question": "火", "answer": "ひ" },
        { "question": "put on the stove", "kanji_question": "火にかけます", "answer": "ひにかけます" },
        { "question": "cook, boil", "kanji_question": "煮ます", "answer": "にます" },
        { "question": "be cooked, be boiled", "kanji_question": "煮えます", "answer": "にえます" },
        { "question": "bowl", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どんぶり" },
        { "question": "pass (time)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "たちます" }
    ],
    "N4L35VQuiz": [
        { "question": "(flowers) bloom", "kanji_question": "咲きます", "answer": "さきます" },
        { "question": "(the colour) change", "kanji_question": "変わります", "answer": "かわります" },
        { "question": "be in trouble, have a problem", "kanji_question": "困ります", "answer": "こまります" },
        { "question": "draw (a circle), mark (with a circle), add", "kanji_question": "付けます", "answer": "つけます" },
        { "question": "recover from (sickness), get well", "kanji_question": "治ります", "answer": "なおります" },
        { "question": "be fixed, be repaired", "kanji_question": "直ります", "answer": "なおります" },
        { "question": "click", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "クリックします" },
        { "question": "input", "kanji_question": "入力します", "answer": "にゅうりょくします" },
        { "question": "correct, right", "kanji_question": "正しい", "answer": "ただしい" },
        { "question": "over there, the other side", "kanji_question": "向こう", "answer": "むこう" },
        { "question": "island", "kanji_question": "島", "answer": "しま" },
        { "question": "port, harbour", "kanji_question": "港", "answer": "みなと" },
        { "question": "neighbourhood, vicinity", "kanji_question": "近所", "answer": "きんじょ" },
        { "question": "rooftop", "kanji_question": "屋上", "answer": "おくじょう" },
        { "question": "overseas", "kanji_question": "海外", "answer": "かいがい" },
        { "question": "mountain climbing", "kanji_question": "山登り", "answer": "やまのぼり" },
        { "question": "history", "kanji_question": "歴史", "answer": "れきし" },
        { "question": "chance, opportunity", "kanji_question": "機会", "answer": "きかい" },
        { "question": "permission", "kanji_question": "許可", "answer": "きょか" },
        { "question": "circle", "kanji_question": "丸", "answer": "まる" },
        { "question": "(kana above or beside kanji indicating its pronunciation)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ふりがな" },
        { "question": "equipment, facilities", "kanji_question": "設備", "answer": "せつび" },
        { "question": "lever", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "レバー" },
        { "question": "key", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "キー" },
        { "question": "curtain", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カーテン" },
        { "question": "string", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ひも" },
        { "question": "rice cooker", "kanji_question": "炊飯器", "answer": "すいはんき" },
        { "question": "leaf", "kanji_question": "葉", "answer": "は" },
        { "question": "old days, ancient times", "kanji_question": "昔", "answer": "むかし" },
        { "question": "more", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "もっと" },
        { "question": "Let's finish now.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "これでおわりましょう。" },
        { "question": "Africa", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "アフリカ" },
        { "question": "in that case", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "それなら" },
        { "question": "overnight bus", "kanji_question": "夜行バス", "answer": "やこうバス" },
        { "question": "Well, let me see. (used when unsure of something)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "さあ" },
        { "question": "travel agency", "kanji_question": "旅行社", "answer": "りょこうしゃ" },
        { "question": "detailed", "kanji_question": "詳しい", "answer": "くわしい" },
        { "question": "ski resort, ski area", "kanji_question": "スキー場", "answer": "スキーじょう" },
        { "question": "vermilion", "kanji_question": "朱", "answer": "しゅ" },
        { "question": "keep company with", "kanji_question": "交わります", "answer": "まじわります" },
        { "question": "proverb", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ことわざ" },
        { "question": "relationship", "kanji_question": "関係", "answer": "かんけい" },
        { "question": "be on good terms with", "kanji_question": "仲よくします", "answer": "なかよくします" },
        { "question": "necessary, essential", "kanji_question": "必要", "answer": "ひつよう" }
    ],
    "N4L36VQuiz": [
        { "question": "encounter (an accident)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あいます" },
        { "question": "save money", "kanji_question": "貯金します", "answer": "ちょきんします" },
        { "question": "pass (7 o'clock)", "kanji_question": "過ぎます", "answer": "すぎます" },
        { "question": "get accustomed to (one's job)", "kanji_question": "慣れます", "answer": "なれます" },
        { "question": "(food) rot", "kanji_question": "腐ります", "answer": "くさります" },
        { "question": "kendo (Japanese style fencing)", "kanji_question": "剣道", "answer": "けんどう" },
        { "question": "judo", "kanji_question": "柔道", "answer": "じゅうどう" },
        { "question": "rush hour", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ラッシュ" },
        { "question": "space, universe", "kanji_question": "宇宙", "answer": "うちゅう" },
        { "question": "a piece of music", "kanji_question": "曲", "answer": "きょく" },
        { "question": "every week", "kanji_question": "毎週", "answer": "まいしゅう" },
        { "question": "every month", "kanji_question": "毎月", "answer": "まいつき" },
        { "question": "every year (1)", "kanji_question": "毎年（１）", "answer": "まいとし" },
        { "question": "every year (2)", "kanji_question": "毎年（２）", "answer": "まいねん" },
        { "question": "these days", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "このごろ" },
        { "question": "finally", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "やっと" },
        { "question": "fairly", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かなり" },
        { "question": "without fail, by any means", "kanji_question": "必ず", "answer": "かならず" },
        { "question": "absolutely", "kanji_question": "絶対に", "answer": "ぜったいに" },
        { "question": "well, skillfully", "kanji_question": "上手に", "answer": "じょうずに" },
        { "question": "as much as possible", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "できるだけ" },
        { "question": "almost all (in affirmative sentences), hardly, scarcely (in negative sentences)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ほとんど" },
        { "question": "Chopin, Polish musician (1810~49)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ショパン" },
        { "question": "visitor, guest, customer, client (respectful equivalent of おきゃくさん)", "kanji_question": "お客様", "answer": "おきゃくさま" },
        { "question": "special", "kanji_question": "特別", "answer": "とくべつ" },
        { "question": "be doing (respectful equivalent of しています)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "していらっしゃいます" },
        { "question": "swimming", "kanji_question": "水泳", "answer": "すいえい" },
        { "question": "be different", "kanji_question": "違います", "answer": "ちがいます" },
        { "question": "You're using, aren't you? (respectful equivalent of つかっているんですね)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "つかっていらっしゃるんですね。" },
        { "question": "challenge", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "チャレンジします" },
        { "question": "spirit, mood", "kanji_question": "気持ち", "answer": "きもち" },
        { "question": "vehicle, means of transportation", "kanji_question": "乗り物", "answer": "のりもの" },
        { "question": "~th century", "kanji_question": "～世紀", "answer": "～せいき" },
        { "question": "far, remote place", "kanji_question": "遠く", "answer": "とおく" },
        { "question": "rare, uncommon", "kanji_question": "珍しい", "answer": "めずらしい" },
        { "question": "locomotive", "kanji_question": "汽車", "answer": "きしゃ" },
        { "question": "steam boat", "kanji_question": "汽船", "answer": "きせん" },
        { "question": "many (people)", "kanji_question": "大勢の～", "answer": "おおぜいの～" },
        { "question": "carry, transport", "kanji_question": "運びます", "answer": "はこびます" },
        { "question": "use", "kanji_question": "利用します", "answer": "りようします" },
        { "question": "freely", "kanji_question": "自由に", "answer": "じゆうに" }
    ],
    "N4L37VQuiz": [
        { "question": "praise", "kanji_question": "褒めます", "answer": "ほめます" },
        { "question": "scold", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "しかります" },
        { "question": "invite, ask someone to join", "kanji_question": "誘います", "answer": "さそいます" },
        { "question": "invite", "kanji_question": "招待します", "answer": "しょうたいします" },
        { "question": "ask, request", "kanji_question": "頼みます", "answer": "たのみます" },
        { "question": "warn, advise", "kanji_question": "注意します", "answer": "ちゅういします" },
        { "question": "rob, steal", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "とります" },
        { "question": "step on", "kanji_question": "踏みます", "answer": "ふみます" },
        { "question": "break, destroy", "kanji_question": "壊します", "answer": "こわします" },
        { "question": "make ~ dirty", "kanji_question": "汚します", "answer": "よごします" },
        { "question": "hold, carry out, practise", "kanji_question": "行います", "answer": "おこないます" },
        { "question": "export", "kanji_question": "輸出します", "answer": "ゆしゅつします" },
        { "question": "import", "kanji_question": "輸入します", "answer": "ゆにゅうします" },
        { "question": "translate", "kanji_question": "翻訳します", "answer": "ほんやくします" },
        { "question": "invent", "kanji_question": "発明します", "answer": "はつめいします" },
        { "question": "discover", "kanji_question": "発見します", "answer": "はっけんします" },
        { "question": "rice", "kanji_question": "米", "answer": "こめ" },
        { "question": "barley, wheat", "kanji_question": "麦", "answer": "むぎ" },
        { "question": "oil", "kanji_question": "石油", "answer": "せきゆ" },
        { "question": "raw material", "kanji_question": "原料", "answer": "げんりょう" },
        { "question": "instant noodles", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "インスタントラーメン" },
        { "question": "date", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "デート" },
        { "question": "thief, robber", "kanji_question": "泥棒", "answer": "どろぼう" },
        { "question": "policeman", "kanji_question": "警官", "answer": "けいかん" },
        { "question": "all over the world", "kanji_question": "世界中", "answer": "せかいじゅう" },
        { "question": "all over ~", "kanji_question": "～中", "answer": "～じゅう" },
        { "question": "~th century", "kanji_question": "～世紀", "answer": "～せいき" },
        { "question": "what language", "kanji_question": "何語", "answer": "なにご" },
        { "question": "somebody", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "だれか" },
        { "question": "Sounds good.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "よかったですね。" },   
        { "question": "Olympic Games", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "オリンピック" },   
        { "question": "World Cup", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ワールドカップ" },   
        { "question": "Portugal", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ポルトガル" },   
        { "question": "Saudi Arabia", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "サウジアラビア" },   
        { "question": "Russia", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ロシア" },   
        { "question": "Ladies and gentlemen, everybody (respect equivalent of みなさん)", "kanji_question": "皆様", "answer": "みなさま" },
        { "question": "(house) burn down", "kanji_question": "焼けます", "answer": "やけます" },
        { "question": "after that, later", "kanji_question": "その後", "answer": "そのご" },
        { "question": "World Heritage Site", "kanji_question": "世界遺産", "answer": "せかいいさん" },
        { "question": "one of the ~", "kanji_question": "～の一つ", "answer": "～のひとつ" },
        { "question": "golden colour", "kanji_question": "金色", "answer": "きんいろ" },
        { "question": "real thing", "kanji_question": "本物", "answer": "ほんもの" },
        { "question": "gold", "kanji_question": "金", "answer": "きん" },
        { "question": "~ kilogrammes, ~ kilometres", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～キロ" },
        { "question": "beautiful, pretty", "kanji_question": "美しい", "answer": "うつくしい" },
        { "question": "gorgeous", "kanji_question": "豪華", "answer": "ごうか" },
        { "question": "engraving, carving, sculpture", "kanji_question": "彫刻", "answer": "ちょうこく" },
        { "question": "tradition, legend", "kanji_question": "言い伝え", "answer": "いいつたえ" },
        { "question": "sleep", "kanji_question": "眠ります", "answer": "ねむります" },
        { "question": "engrave, carve", "kanji_question": "彫ります", "answer": "ほります" },
        { "question": "colleague, friend", "kanji_question": "仲間", "answer": "なかま" },
        { "question": "however, but", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "しかし" },
        { "question": "after that", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そのあと" },
        { "question": "with all one's effort", "kanji_question": "一生懸命", "answer": "いっしょうけんめい" },
        { "question": "mouse", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ねずみ" },
        { "question": "There is not a single.", "kanji_question": "一匹もいません。", "answer": "いっぴきもいません。" }
    ],
    "N4L38VQuiz": [
        { "question": "join (a tour), participate, attend", "kanji_question": "参加します", "answer": "さんかします" },
        { "question": "breed, bring up", "kanji_question": "育てます", "answer": "そだてます" },
        { "question": "carry, transport", "kanji_question": "運びます", "answer": "はこびます" },
        { "question": "enter hospital", "kanji_question": "入院します", "answer": "にゅういんします" },
        { "question": "leave hospital", "kanji_question": "退院します", "answer": "たいいんします" },
        { "question": "turn on (the power switch)", "kanji_question": "入れます", "answer": "いれます" },
        { "question": "turn off (the power switch)", "kanji_question": "切ります", "answer": "きります" },
        { "question": "lock", "kanji_question": "掛けます", "answer": "かけます" },
        { "question": "tell (a lie)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "つきます" },
        { "question": "pleasant, agreeable", "kanji_question": "気持ちがいい", "answer": "きもちがいい" },
        { "question": "unpleasant, disgusting", "kanji_question": "気持ちが悪い", "answer": "きもちがわるい" },
        { "question": "large ~, big ~", "kanji_question": "大きな～", "answer": "おおきな～" },
        { "question": "small ~, little ~", "kanji_question": "小さな～", "answer": "ちいさな～" },
        { "question": "baby", "kanji_question": "赤ちゃん", "answer": "あかちゃん" },
        { "question": "elementary school", "kanji_question": "小学校", "answer": "しょうがっこう" },
        { "question": "junior high school", "kanji_question": "中学校", "answer": "ちゅうがっこう" },
        { "question": "the area in front of the station", "kanji_question": "駅前", "answer": "えきまえ" },
        { "question": "seaside, seashore", "kanji_question": "海岸", "answer": "かいがん" },
        { "question": "factory", "kanji_question": "工場", "answer": "こうじょう" },
        { "question": "village", "kanji_question": "村", "answer": "むら" },
        { "question": "hiragana and katakana script", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かな" },
        { "question": "ring", "kanji_question": "指輪", "answer": "ゆびわ" },
        { "question": "power switch", "kanji_question": "電源", "answer": "でんげん" },
        { "question": "habit", "kanji_question": "習慣", "answer": "しゅうかん" },
        { "question": "health", "kanji_question": "健康", "answer": "けんこう" },
        { "question": "made in ~", "kanji_question": "～製", "answer": "～せい" },
        { "question": "the year before last", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おととし" },
        { "question": "Oops!/Oh, no! (used when one has made a mistake)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「あ、」いけない。" },
        { "question": "Excuse me (for leaving before you).", "kanji_question": "お先に失礼します。", "answer": "おさきにしつれいします。" },
        { "question": "circular", "kanji_question": "回覧", "answer": "かいらん" },
        { "question": "study room, professor's office, laboratory", "kanji_question": "研究室", "answer": "けんきゅうしつ" },
        { "question": "neatly, tidily", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "きちんと" },
        { "question": "sort (things) out, put in order, tidy up", "kanji_question": "整理します", "answer": "せいりします" },
        { "question": "method", "kanji_question": "方法", "answer": "ほうほう" },
        { "question": "entitled ~, named ~, called ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～という" },
        { "question": "(counter for books, etc.)", "kanji_question": "～冊", "answer": "～さつ" },
        { "question": "seal, stamp", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "はんこ" },
        { "question": "affix (a seal), stamp", "kanji_question": "押します", "answer": "おします" },
        { "question": "twins", "kanji_question": "双子", "answer": "ふたご" },
        { "question": "sisters", "kanji_question": "姉妹", "answer": "しまい" },
        { "question": "fifth grade, fifth year", "kanji_question": "5年生", "answer": "５ねんせい" },
        { "question": "resemble, be like", "kanji_question": "似ています", "answer": "にています" },
        { "question": "character", "kanji_question": "性格", "answer": "せいかく" },
        { "question": "quiet, gentle", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おとなしい" },
        { "question": "kind, gentle, tender-hearted", "kanji_question": "優しい", "answer": "やさしい" },
        { "question": "take care of", "kanji_question": "世話をします", "answer": "せわをします" },
        { "question": "time passes by ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "じかんがたちます" },
        { "question": "like very much", "kanji_question": "大好き", "answer": "だいすき" },
        { "question": "~ points", "kanji_question": "点", "answer": "てん" },
        { "question": "tough, strong-willed", "kanji_question": "気が強い", "answer": "きがつよい" },
        { "question": "quarrel, fight", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "けんかします" },
        { "question": "mysterious, strange", "kanji_question": "不思議", "answer": "ふしぎ" },
        { "question": "age", "kanji_question": "年齢", "answer": "ねんれい" },
        { "question": "way (of doing something)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "しかた" }
    ],
    "N4L39VQuiz": [
        { "question": "answer (a question)", "kanji_question": "答えます", "answer": "こたえます" },
        { "question": "(a building) fall down", "kanji_question": "倒れます", "answer": "たおれます" },
        { "question": "pass (along a street)", "kanji_question": "通ります", "answer": "とおります" },
        { "question": "die", "kanji_question": "死にます", "answer": "しにます" },
        { "question": "be surprised", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "びっくりします" },
        { "question": "be disappointed", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "がっかりします" },
        { "question": "be relieved", "kanji_question": "安心します", "answer": "あんしんします" },
        { "question": "quarrel, fight", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "けんかします" },
        { "question": "divorce", "kanji_question": "離婚します", "answer": "りこんします" },
        { "question": "get fat, gain weight", "kanji_question": "太ります", "answer": "ふとります" },
        { "question": "get slim, lose weight", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "やせます" },
        { "question": "complicated, complex", "kanji_question": "複雑", "answer": "ふくざつ" },
        { "question": "obstructive, in the way", "kanji_question": "邪魔", "answer": "じゃま" },
        { "question": "hard, tough, solid", "kanji_question": "硬い", "answer": "かたい" },
        { "question": "soft, tender", "kanji_question": "軟らかい", "answer": "やわらかい" },
        { "question": "dirty", "kanji_question": "汚い", "answer": "きたない" },
        { "question": "glad, happy", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うれしい" },
        { "question": "sad", "kanji_question": "悲しい", "answer": "かなしい" },
        { "question": "embarrassed, ashamed", "kanji_question": "恥ずかしい", "answer": "はずかしい" },
        { "question": "Prime Minister", "kanji_question": "首相", "answer": "しゅしょう" },
        { "question": "earthquake", "kanji_question": "地震", "answer": "じしん" },
        { "question": "tsunami, tidal wave", "kanji_question": "津波", "answer": "つなみ" },
        { "question": "typhoon", "kanji_question": "台風", "answer": "たいふう" },
        { "question": "thunder", "kanji_question": "雷", "answer": "かみなり" },
        { "question": "fire", "kanji_question": "火事", "answer": "かじ" },
        { "question": "accident", "kanji_question": "事故", "answer": "じこ" },
        { "question": "hiking", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ハイキング" },
        { "question": "a meeting arranged with a view to marriage", "kanji_question": "「お」見合い", "answer": "「お」みあい" },
        { "question": "operation", "kanji_question": "操作", "answer": "そうさ" },
        { "question": "venue, event location", "kanji_question": "会場", "answer": "かいじょう" },
        { "question": "charge, fare, fee", "kanji_question": "～代", "answer": "～だい" },
        { "question": "-er (e.g. baker, grocer, etc.)", "kanji_question": "～屋", "answer": "～や" },
        { "question": "front desk, reception desk", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "フロント" },
        { "question": "room number", "kanji_question": "～号室", "answer": "～ごうしつ" },
        { "question": "towel", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "タオル" },
        { "question": "soap", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "せっけん" },
        { "question": "a great number (of people)", "kanji_question": "おおぜい", "answer": "おおぜい" },
        { "question": "Thank you for your hard work.", "kanji_question": "お疲れさまでした。", "answer": "おつかれさまでした。" },
        { "question": "I'm coming. (humble equivalent of いきます)", "kanji_question": "伺います。", "answer": "うかがいます。" },
        { "question": "on the way, in the midst of", "kanji_question": "途中で", "answer": "とちゅうで" },
        { "question": "truck, lorry", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "トラック" },
        { "question": "bump, collide", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ぶつかります" },
        { "question": "adult", "kanji_question": "大人", "answer": "おとな" },
        { "question": "however, but", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "しかし" },
        { "question": "and", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "また" },
        { "question": "Western clothes", "kanji_question": "洋服", "answer": "ようふく" },
        { "question": "be Westernized", "kanji_question": "西洋化します", "answer": "せいようかします" },
        { "question": "fit, suit", "kanji_question": "合います", "answer": "あいます" },
        { "question": "now", "kanji_question": "今では", "answer": "いまでは" },
        { "question": "coming-of-age celebration", "kanji_question": "成人式", "answer": "せいじんしき" },
        { "question": "traditional", "kanji_question": "伝統的", "answer": "でんとうてき" }
    ],
    "N4L40VQuiz": [
        { "question": "count", "kanji_question": "数えます", "answer": "かぞえます" },
        { "question": "measure", "kanji_question": "測ります", "answer": "はかります" },
        { "question": "weigh", "kanji_question": "量ります", "answer": "はかります" },
        { "question": "confirm, make sure", "kanji_question": "確かめます", "answer": "たしかめます" },
        { "question": "(the size) fit", "kanji_question": "合います", "answer": "あいます" },
        { "question": "depart", "kanji_question": "出発します", "answer": "しゅっぱつします" },
        { "question": "arrive", "kanji_question": "到着します", "answer": "とうちゃくします" },
        { "question": "get drunk", "kanji_question": "酔います", "answer": "よいます" },
        { "question": "go well", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うまくいきます" },
        { "question": "(problems) be on the test", "kanji_question": "出ます", "answer": "でます" },
        { "question": "consult, discuss", "kanji_question": "相談します", "answer": "そうだんします" },
        { "question": "necessary", "kanji_question": "必要", "answer": "ひつよう" },
        { "question": "weather forecast", "kanji_question": "天気予報", "answer": "てんきよほう" },
        { "question": "year-end party", "kanji_question": "忘年会", "answer": "ぼうねんかい" },
        { "question": "New Year's party", "kanji_question": "新年会", "answer": "しんねんかい" },
        { "question": "second party", "kanji_question": "二次会", "answer": "にじかい" },
        { "question": "presentation meeting", "kanji_question": "発表会", "answer": "はっぴょうかい" },
        { "question": "rally, convention, mass meeting", "kanji_question": "大会", "answer": "たいかい" },
        { "question": "marathon", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "マラソン" },
        { "question": "contest", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "コンテスト" },
        { "question": "face, front", "kanji_question": "表", "answer": "おもて" },
        { "question": "back (side)", "kanji_question": "裏", "answer": "うら" },
        { "question": "mistake", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まちがい" },
        { "question": "defect, wound, scratch", "kanji_question": "傷", "answer": "きず" },
        { "question": "trousers", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ズボン" },
        { "question": "elderly person", "kanji_question": "「お」年寄り", "answer": "「お」としより" },
        { "question": "length", "kanji_question": "長さ", "answer": "ながさ" },
        { "question": "weight", "kanji_question": "重さ", "answer": "おもさ" },
        { "question": "height", "kanji_question": "高さ", "answer": "たかさ" },
        { "question": "size, scale", "kanji_question": "大きさ", "answer": "おおきさ" },
        { "question": "flight, flight number", "kanji_question": "便", "answer": "びん" },
        { "question": "(counter for small objects)", "kanji_question": "～個", "answer": "～こ" },
        { "question": "(counter for long objects)", "kanji_question": "～本", "answer": "～ほん" },
        { "question": "~ glass or cup of (counter for full cups, glasses, etc.)", "kanji_question": "～杯", "answer": "～はい" },
        { "question": "~ centimetres", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～センチ" },
        { "question": "~ millimetres", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～ミリ" },
        { "question": "~ grammes", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～グラム" },
        { "question": "not less than ~, over ~", "kanji_question": "～以上", "answer": "～いじょう" },
        { "question": "not more than ~, under ~", "kanji_question": "～以下", "answer": "～いか" },
        { "question": "How is ~? (polite equivalent of どうですか)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どうでしょうか。" },
        { "question": "test, examination", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "テスト" },
        { "question": "performance, score, result", "kanji_question": "成績", "answer": "せいせき" },
        { "question": "by the way", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ところで" },
        { "question": "come (respectful equivalent of きます)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いらっしゃいます" },
        { "question": "situation, condition, appearance", "kanji_question": "様子", "answer": "ようす" },
        { "question": "incident, case", "kanji_question": "事件", "answer": "じけん" },
        { "question": "motorcycle", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "オートバイ" },
        { "question": "bomb", "kanji_question": "爆弾", "answer": "ばくだん" },
        { "question": "load, pile up", "kanji_question": "積みます", "answer": "つみます" },
        { "question": "driver", "kanji_question": "運転手", "answer": "うんてんしゅ" },
        { "question": "remote", "kanji_question": "離れた", "answer": "はなれた" },
        { "question": "suddenly", "kanji_question": "急に", "answer": "きゅうに" },
        { "question": "start, operate, move", "kanji_question": "動かします", "answer": "うごかします" },
        { "question": "with all one's effort", "kanji_question": "一生懸命", "answer": "いっしょうけんめい" },
        { "question": "offender, criminal", "kanji_question": "犯人", "answer": "はんにん" },
        { "question": "man", "kanji_question": "男", "answer": "おとこ" },
        { "question": "obtain, get", "kanji_question": "手に入れます", "answer": "てにいれます" },
        { "question": "even now", "kanji_question": "今でも", "answer": "いまでも" }
    ],
    "N4L41VQuiz": [
        { "question": "receive (humble equivalent of もらいます)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いただきます" },
        { "question": "give (respectful equivalent of くれます)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "くださいます" },
        { "question": "give (to a younger person, subordinate, animals or plants)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "やります" },
        { "question": "raise, lift up", "kanji_question": "上げます", "answer": "あげます" },
        { "question": "lower, pull down", "kanji_question": "下げます", "answer": "さげます" },
        { "question": "be kind to", "kanji_question": "親切にします", "answer": "しんせつにします" },
        { "question": "lovely, cute", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かわいい" },
        { "question": "rare, uncommon", "kanji_question": "珍しい", "answer": "めずらしい" },
        { "question": "celebration, gift", "kanji_question": "お祝い", "answer": "おいわい" },
        { "question": "money given as a New Year's gift", "kanji_question": "お年玉", "answer": "おとしだま" },
        { "question": "expression of sympathy, consolatory gift to a sick person", "kanji_question": "「お」見舞い", "answer": "「お」みまい" },
        { "question": "interest", "kanji_question": "興味", "answer": "きょうみ" },
        { "question": "information", "kanji_question": "情報", "answer": "じょうほう" },
        { "question": "grammar", "kanji_question": "文法", "answer": "ぶんぽう" },
        { "question": "pronunciation", "kanji_question": "発音", "answer": "はつおん" },
        { "question": "ape, monkey", "kanji_question": "猿", "answer": "さる" },
        { "question": "feed, bait", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "えさ" },
        { "question": "toy", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おもちゃ" },
        { "question": "picture book", "kanji_question": "絵本", "answer": "えほん" },
        { "question": "picture postcard", "kanji_question": "絵はがき", "answer": "えはがき" },
        { "question": "screwdriver", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ドライバー" },
        { "question": "handkerchief", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ハンカチ" },
        { "question": "socks, stockings", "kanji_question": "靴下", "answer": "くつした" },
        { "question": "gloves", "kanji_question": "手袋", "answer": "てぶくろ" },
        { "question": "preschool, kindergarten", "kanji_question": "幼稚園", "answer": "ようちえん" },
        { "question": "heating", "kanji_question": "暖房", "answer": "だんぼう" },
        { "question": "air-conditioning", "kanji_question": "冷房", "answer": "れいぼう" },
        { "question": "temperature", "kanji_question": "温度", "answer": "おんど" },
        { "question": "(my) grandfather", "kanji_question": "祖父", "answer": "そふ" },
        { "question": "(my) grandmother", "kanji_question": "祖母", "answer": "そぼ" },
        { "question": "(my) grandchild", "kanji_question": "孫", "answer": "まご" },
        { "question": "(someone else's) grandchild", "kanji_question": "お孫さん", "answer": "おまごさん" },
        { "question": "(my) uncle", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おじ" },
        { "question": "(someone else's) uncle", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おじさん" },
        { "question": "(my) aunt", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おば" },
        { "question": "(someone else's) aunt", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おばさん" },
        { "question": "janitor, caretaker", "kanji_question": "管理人", "answer": "かんりにん" },
        { "question": "(suffix added to a person's job title as a polite way of referring to them)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～さん" },
        { "question": "the other day", "kanji_question": "この間", "answer": "このあいだ" },
        { "question": "a few words", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ひとこと" },
        { "question": "each", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～ずつ" },
        { "question": "couple", "kanji_question": "二人", "answer": "ふたり" },
        { "question": "home (respectful equivalent of うち or いえ)", "kanji_question": "お宅", "answer": "おたく" },
        { "question": "I hope you will be very happy.", "kanji_question": "どうぞお幸せに。", "answer": "どうぞおしあわせに。" },
        { "question": "old tale, folklore", "kanji_question": "昔話", "answer": "むかしばなし" },
        { "question": "a certain ~, one ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ある～" },
        { "question": "man", "kanji_question": "男", "answer": "おとこ" },
        { "question": "children", "kanji_question": "子どもたち", "answer": "こどもたち" },
        { "question": "bully, abuse, ill-treat", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いじめます" },
        { "question": "turtle, tortoise", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かめ" },
        { "question": "save, help", "kanji_question": "助けます", "answer": "たすけます" },
        { "question": "kind, gentle, tender-hearted", "kanji_question": "優しい", "answer": "やさしい" },
        { "question": "princess", "kanji_question": "お姫様", "answer": "おひめさま" },
        { "question": "live, lead a life", "kanji_question": "暮らします", "answer": "くらします" },
        { "question": "land, shore", "kanji_question": "陸", "answer": "りく" },
        { "question": "and, then", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "すると" },
        { "question": "smoke", "kanji_question": "煙", "answer": "けむり" },
        { "question": "pure white", "kanji_question": "真っ白", "answer": "まっしろ" },
        { "question": "content", "kanji_question": "中身", "answer": "なかみ" }
    ],
    "N4L42VQuiz": [
        { "question": "wrap", "kanji_question": "包みます", "answer": "つつみます" },
        { "question": "boil", "kanji_question": "沸かします", "answer": "わかします" },
        { "question": "mix", "kanji_question": "混ぜます", "answer": "まぜます" },
        { "question": "calculate", "kanji_question": "計算します", "answer": "けいさんします" },
        { "question": "stand in a queue, line up", "kanji_question": "並びます", "answer": "ならびます" },
        { "question": "strong, healthy", "kanji_question": "丈夫", "answer": "じょうぶ" },
        { "question": "apartment, flat", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "アパート" },
        { "question": "lawyer, attorney, solicitor, barrister", "kanji_question": "弁護士", "answer": "べんごし" },
        { "question": "musician", "kanji_question": "音楽家", "answer": "おんがくか" },
        { "question": "children", "kanji_question": "子どもたち", "answer": "こどもたち" },
        { "question": "nature", "kanji_question": "自然", "answer": "しぜん" },
        { "question": "education", "kanji_question": "教育", "answer": "きょういく" },
        { "question": "culture", "kanji_question": "文化", "answer": "ぶんか" },
        { "question": "society", "kanji_question": "社会", "answer": "しゃかい" },
        { "question": "politics", "kanji_question": "政治", "answer": "せいじ" },
        { "question": "law", "kanji_question": "法律", "answer": "ほうりつ" },
        { "question": "war", "kanji_question": "戦争", "answer": "せんそう" },
        { "question": "peace", "kanji_question": "平和", "answer": "へいわ" },
        { "question": "purpose", "kanji_question": "目的", "answer": "もくてき" },
        { "question": "thesis, academic paper", "kanji_question": "論文", "answer": "ろんぶん" },
        { "question": "pleasure, enjoyment, expectation", "kanji_question": "楽しみ", "answer": "たのしみ" },
        { "question": "mixer, blender", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ミキサー" },
        { "question": "kettle", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "やかん" },
        { "question": "lid, cover, cap", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ふた" },
        { "question": "cap opener, bottle opener, corkscrew", "kanji_question": "栓抜き", "answer": "せんぬき" },
        { "question": "can opener", "kanji_question": "缶切り", "answer": "かんきり" },
        { "question": "canned food, tinned food", "kanji_question": "缶詰", "answer": "かんづめ" },
        { "question": "envelope for a gift of money", "kanji_question": "のし袋", "answer": "のしぶくろ" },
        { "question": "wrapping cloth used to carry things", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ふろしき" },
        { "question": "abacus", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "そろばん" },
        { "question": "(clinical) thermometer", "kanji_question": "体温計", "answer": "たいおんけい" },
        { "question": "material, ingredient", "kanji_question": "材料", "answer": "ざいりょう" },
        { "question": "a certain ~, one ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ある～" },
        { "question": "with all one's effort", "kanji_question": "一生懸命", "answer": "いっしょうけんめい" },
        { "question": "why", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "なぜ" },
        { "question": "how much, how many", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どのくらい" },
        { "question": "(bonus) be paid", "kanji_question": "出ます", "answer": "でます" },
        { "question": "half", "kanji_question": "半分", "answer": "はんぶん" },
        { "question": "loan", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ローン" },
        { "question": "instant noodles sold in a ready-to-use disposable container, pot noodles", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カップめん" },
        { "question": "world's first", "kanji_question": "世界初", "answer": "せかいはつ" },
        { "question": "by ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～によって" },
        { "question": "bowl, ceramic bowl", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どんぶり" },
        { "question": "noodles", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "めん" },
        { "question": "spread", "kanji_question": "広めます", "answer": "ひろめます" },
        { "question": "market survey, market research", "kanji_question": "市場調査", "answer": "しじょうちょうさ" },
        { "question": "break", "kanji_question": "割ります", "answer": "わります" },
        { "question": "pour", "kanji_question": "注ぎます", "answer": "そそぎます" }
    ],
    "N4L43VQuiz": [
        { "question": "(exports) increase", "kanji_question": "増えます", "answer": "ふえます" },
        { "question": "(exports) decrease", "kanji_question": "減ります", "answer": "へります" },
        { "question": "(the price) rise", "kanji_question": "上がります", "answer": "あがります" },
        { "question": "(the price) fall, drop", "kanji_question": "下がります", "answer": "さがります" },
        { "question": "(a string) break, snap", "kanji_question": "切れます", "answer": "きれます" },
        { "question": "(a button) come off", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "とれます" },
        { "question": "(baggage) fall down", "kanji_question": "落ちます", "answer": "おちます" },
        { "question": "(petrol, gasoline) run out, be lost", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "なくなります" },
        { "question": "strange, peculiar", "kanji_question": "変", "answer": "へん" },
        { "question": "happy", "kanji_question": "幸せ", "answer": "しあわせ" },
        { "question": "easy", "kanji_question": "楽", "answer": "らく" },
        { "question": "tasty", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うまい" },
        { "question": "not tasty", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "まずい" },
        { "question": "boring, uninteresting, trivial", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "つまらない" },
        { "question": "kind, gentle, tender-hearted", "kanji_question": "優しい", "answer": "やさしい" },
        { "question": "petrol, gasoline", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ガソリン" },
        { "question": "fire", "kanji_question": "火", "answer": "ひ" },
        { "question": "pamphlet", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パンフレット" },
        { "question": "at any moment (used to describe a situation just before it changes)", "kanji_question": "今にも", "answer": "いまにも" },
        { "question": "Oh!/Wow!", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "わあ" },
        { "question": "rose", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ばら" },
        { "question": "driving", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ドライブ" },
        { "question": "reason", "kanji_question": "理由", "answer": "りゆう" },
        { "question": "apologize", "kanji_question": "謝ります", "answer": "あやまります" },
        { "question": "get acquainted", "kanji_question": "知り合います", "answer": "しりあいます" }
    ],
    "N4L44VQuiz": [
        { "question": "cry", "kanji_question": "泣きます", "answer": "なきます" },
        { "question": "laugh, smile", "kanji_question": "笑います", "answer": "わらいます" },
        { "question": "sleep", "kanji_question": "眠ります", "answer": "ねむります" },
        { "question": "(a shirt) dry", "kanji_question": "乾きます", "answer": "かわきます" },
        { "question": "(a shirt) get wet", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ぬれます" },
        { "question": "slip", "kanji_question": "滑ります", "answer": "すべります" },
        { "question": "(an accident) happen", "kanji_question": "起きます", "answer": "おきます" },
        { "question": "adjust", "kanji_question": "調節します", "answer": "ちょうせつします" },
        { "question": "safe", "kanji_question": "安全", "answer": "あんぜん" },
        { "question": "dangerous", "kanji_question": "危険", "answer": "きけん" },
        { "question": "strong (taste), dark (colour), thick (liquid)", "kanji_question": "濃い", "answer": "こい" },
        { "question": "weak (taste), light (colour), thin (liquid)", "kanji_question": "薄い", "answer": "うすい" },
        { "question": "thick", "kanji_question": "厚い", "answer": "あつい" },
        { "question": "thick (of large diameter)", "kanji_question": "太い", "answer": "ふとい" },
        { "question": "thin (of small diameter)", "kanji_question": "細い", "answer": "ほそい" },
        { "question": "air", "kanji_question": "空気", "answer": "くうき" },
        { "question": "tear", "kanji_question": "涙", "answer": "なみだ" },
        { "question": "Japanese dish", "kanji_question": "和食", "answer": "わしょく" },
        { "question": "Western dish", "kanji_question": "洋食", "answer": "ようしょく" },
        { "question": "side dish", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おかず" },
        { "question": "quantity", "kanji_question": "量", "answer": "りょう" },
        { "question": "~ times", "kanji_question": "～倍", "answer": "～ばい" },
        { "question": "single room", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "シングル" },
        { "question": "twin-bedded room", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ツイン" },
        { "question": "washing, laundry", "kanji_question": "洗濯物", "answer": "せんたくもの" },
        { "question": "DVD", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "DVD" },
        { "question": "What can I do for you? (respectful)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どうなさいますか。" },
        { "question": "haircut", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "カット" },
        { "question": "shampoo", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "シャンプー" },
        { "question": "How would you like it done? (respectful)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どういうふうになさいますか。" },
        { "question": "short", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ショート" },
        { "question": "Do it like ~.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～みたいにしてください。" },
        { "question": "Would this be all right? (polite)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "これでよろしいでしょうか。" },
        { "question": "Thank you for your patience. (shop assistant to customer)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "「どうも」おつかれさまでした。" },
        { "question": "dislike", "kanji_question": "嫌がります", "answer": "いやがります" },
        { "question": "and", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "また" },
        { "question": "well", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "うまく" },
        { "question": "order", "kanji_question": "順序", "answer": "じゅんじょ" },
        { "question": "relieved", "kanji_question": "安心", "answer": "あんしん" },
        { "question": "expression", "kanji_question": "表現", "answer": "ひょうげん" },
        { "question": "for example", "kanji_question": "例えば", "answer": "たとえば" },
        { "question": "part, separate", "kanji_question": "別れます", "answer": "わかれます" },
        { "question": "these", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "これら" },
        { "question": "unlucky, ill-omened", "kanji_question": "縁起が悪い", "answer": "えんぎがわるい" }
    ],
    "N4L45VQuiz": [
        { "question": "believe, trust", "kanji_question": "信じます", "answer": "しんじます" },
        { "question": "cancel", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "キャンセルします" },
        { "question": "inform", "kanji_question": "知らせます", "answer": "しらせます" },
        { "question": "guarantee", "kanji_question": "保証書", "answer": "ほしょうしょ" },
        { "question": "receipt", "kanji_question": "領収書", "answer": "りょうしゅうしょ" },
        { "question": "camp", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "キャンプ" },
        { "question": "calling off, cancelling, suspension", "kanji_question": "中止", "answer": "ちゅうし" },
        { "question": "point, score", "kanji_question": "点", "answer": "てん" },
        { "question": "plum (blossom)", "kanji_question": "梅", "answer": "うめ" },
        { "question": "the emergency police telephone number", "kanji_question": "１１０番", "answer": "１１０ばん" },
        { "question": "the emergency fire service telephone number", "kanji_question": "１１９番", "answer": "１１９ばん" },
        { "question": "suddenly", "kanji_question": "急に", "answer": "きゅうに" },
        { "question": "unreasonably", "kanji_question": "無理に", "answer": "むりに" },
        { "question": "be looking forward to, be expecting", "kanji_question": "楽しみにしています", "answer": "たのしみにしています" },
        { "question": "That's all.", "kanji_question": "以上です。", "answer": "いじょうです。" },
        { "question": "person in charge, attendant, organiser", "kanji_question": "係員", "answer": "かかりいん" },
        { "question": "course, route", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "コース" },
        { "question": "start", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スタート" },
        { "question": "~th (ranking)", "kanji_question": "～位", "answer": "～い" },
        { "question": "win the championship, come first", "kanji_question": "優勝します", "answer": "ゆうしょうします" },
        { "question": "trouble, worry", "kanji_question": "悩み", "answer": "なやみ" },
        { "question": "alarm clock", "kanji_question": "目覚まし「時計」", "answer": "めざまし「どけい」" },
        { "question": "wake up", "kanji_question": "目が覚めます", "answer": "めがさめます" },
        { "question": "university student", "kanji_question": "大学生", "answer": "だいがくせい" },
        { "question": "answer, reply", "kanji_question": "回答", "answer": "かいとう" },
        { "question": "ring", "kanji_question": "鳴ります", "answer": "なります" },
        { "question": "set", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "セットします" },
        { "question": "nevertheless, for all that", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "それでも" }
    ],
    "N4L46VQuiz": [
        { "question": "hand over", "kanji_question": "渡します", "answer": "わたします" },
        { "question": "come back", "kanji_question": "帰ってきます", "answer": "かえってきます" },
        { "question": "(a bus) leave, depart", "kanji_question": "出ます", "answer": "でます" },
        { "question": "(parcels) be delivered", "kanji_question": "届きます", "answer": "とどきます" },
        { "question": "enter (a university)", "kanji_question": "入学します", "answer": "にゅうがくします" },
        { "question": "graduate (from a university)", "kanji_question": "卒業します", "answer": "そつぎょうします" },
        { "question": "bake, grill, roast", "kanji_question": "焼きます", "answer": "やきます" },
        { "question": "(bread) be baked", "kanji_question": "焼けます", "answer": "やけます" },
        { "question": "(meat) be roasted, be grilled", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "やけます" },
        { "question": "absence", "kanji_question": "留守", "answer": "るす" },
        { "question": "(package delivered by) home delivery service", "kanji_question": "宅配便", "answer": "たくはいびん" },
        { "question": "cause", "kanji_question": "原因", "answer": "げんいん" },
        { "question": "my side", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "こちら" },
        { "question": "the place around ~, where ~ is/are, by the ~", "kanji_question": "～の所", "answer": "～のところ" },
        { "question": "half a year", "kanji_question": "半年", "answer": "はんとし" },
        { "question": "just, exactly", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ちょうど" },
        { "question": "just now (used with the past tense; indicates completion)", "kanji_question": "たった今", "answer": "たったいま" },
        { "question": "Have you got a moment?", "kanji_question": "今いいですか。", "answer": "いまいいですか。" },
        { "question": "gas service centre", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ガスサービスセンター" },
        { "question": "gas range, gas cooker", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ガスレンジ" },
        { "question": "condition", "kanji_question": "具合", "answer": "ぐあい" },
        { "question": "I'm sorry.", "kanji_question": "申し訳ありません。", "answer": "もうしわけありません。" },
        { "question": "Who is this, please?", "kanji_question": "どちら様でしょうか。", "answer": "どちらさまでしょうか。" },
        { "question": "Sorry to have kept you waiting.", "kanji_question": "お待たせしました。", "answer": "おまたせしました。" },
        { "question": "head for", "kanji_question": "向かいます", "answer": "むかいます" },
        { "question": "be lucky", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ついています" },
        { "question": "floor", "kanji_question": "床", "answer": "ゆか" },
        { "question": "fall down, fall over", "kanji_question": "転びます", "answer": "ころびます" },
        { "question": "bell", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ベル" },
        { "question": "ring", "kanji_question": "鳴ります", "answer": "なります" },
        { "question": "in a hurry", "kanji_question": "慌てて", "answer": "あわてて" },
        { "question": "in order", "kanji_question": "順番に", "answer": "じゅんばんに" },
        { "question": "incident", "kanji_question": "出来事", "answer": "できごと" }
    ],
    "N4L47VQuiz": [
        { "question": "(wind) blow", "kanji_question": "吹きます", "answer": "ふきます" },
        { "question": "(rubbish) burn", "kanji_question": "燃えます", "answer": "もえます" },
        { "question": "pass away (euphemistic equivalent of しにます)", "kanji_question": "亡くなります", "answer": "なくなります" },
        { "question": "(people) gather", "kanji_question": "集まります", "answer": "あつまります" },
        { "question": "(people) part, separate", "kanji_question": "別れます", "answer": "わかれます" },
        { "question": "(sound/voice) be heard", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "します" },
        { "question": "taste", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "します" },
        { "question": "smell", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "します" },
        { "question": "strict, hard", "kanji_question": "厳しい", "answer": "きびしい" },
        { "question": "terrible, severe", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ひどい" },
        { "question": "frightening, horrible", "kanji_question": "怖い", "answer": "こわい" },
        { "question": "experiment", "kanji_question": "実験", "answer": "じっけん" },
        { "question": "data", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "データ" },
        { "question": "population", "kanji_question": "人口", "answer": "じんこう" },
        { "question": "smell", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "におい" },
        { "question": "science", "kanji_question": "科学", "answer": "かがく" },
        { "question": "medicine, medical science", "kanji_question": "医学", "answer": "いがく" },
        { "question": "literature", "kanji_question": "文学", "answer": "ぶんがく" },
        { "question": "patrol car, police car", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "パトカー" },
        { "question": "ambulance", "kanji_question": "救急車", "answer": "きゅうきゅうしゃ" },
        { "question": "approval, agreement", "kanji_question": "賛成", "answer": "さんせい" },
        { "question": "objection, opposition", "kanji_question": "反対", "answer": "はんたい" },
        { "question": "president", "kanji_question": "大統領", "answer": "だいとうりょう" },
        { "question": "according to ~ (indicates that the source of information)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～によると" },
        { "question": "get engaged", "kanji_question": "婚約します", "answer": "こんやくします" },
        { "question": "it seems that (used when making a tentative judgement)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どうも" },
        { "question": "sweetheart, boyfriend, girlfriend", "kanji_question": "恋人", "answer": "こいびと" },
        { "question": "the other person", "kanji_question": "相手", "answer": "あいて" },
        { "question": "get acquainted", "kanji_question": "知り合います", "answer": "しりあいます" },
        { "question": "makeup", "kanji_question": "化粧", "answer": "けしょう" },
        { "question": "take care of", "kanji_question": "世話をします", "answer": "せわをします" },
        { "question": "female, woman", "kanji_question": "女性", "answer": "じょせい" },
        { "question": "male, man", "kanji_question": "男性", "answer": "だんせい" },
        { "question": "long life", "kanji_question": "長生き", "answer": "ながいき" },
        { "question": "reason", "kanji_question": "理由", "answer": "りゆう" },
        { "question": "relationship", "kanji_question": "関係", "answer": "かんけい" }
    ],
    "N4L48VQuiz": [
        { "question": "put down, lower, unload", "kanji_question": "降ろします、下ろします", "answer": "おろします" },
        { "question": "deliver", "kanji_question": "届けます", "answer": "とどけます" },
        { "question": "take care of", "kanji_question": "世話をします", "answer": "せわをします" },
        { "question": "record", "kanji_question": "録音します", "answer": "ろくおんします" },
        { "question": "unwilling, reluctant", "kanji_question": "嫌", "answer": "いや" },
        { "question": "cram school", "kanji_question": "塾", "answer": "じゅく" },
        { "question": "pupil", "kanji_question": "生徒", "answer": "せいと" },
        { "question": "file", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ファイル" },
        { "question": "freely", "kanji_question": "自由に", "answer": "じゆうに" },
        { "question": "for ~ (referring to duration)", "kanji_question": "～間", "answer": "～かん" },
        { "question": "That's good.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いいことですね。" },
        { "question": "Are you busy? (used when talking to someone senior or older)", "kanji_question": "お忙しいですか。", "answer": "おいそがしいですか。" },
        { "question": "business, sales", "kanji_question": "営業", "answer": "えいぎょう" },
        { "question": "by that time", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "それまでに" },
        { "question": "It's all right./I don't mind.", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かまいません。" },
        { "question": "enjoy oneself", "kanji_question": "楽しみます", "answer": "たのしみます" },
        { "question": "parent", "kanji_question": "親", "answer": "おや" },
        { "question": "pupil, elementary schoolchild", "kanji_question": "小学生", "answer": "しょうがくせい" },
        { "question": "~ percent", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～パーセント" },
        { "question": "next", "kanji_question": "その次", "answer": "そのつぎ" },
        { "question": "calligraphy", "kanji_question": "習字", "answer": "しゅうじ" },
        { "question": "normal, usual", "kanji_question": "普通の", "answer": "ふつうの" }
    ],
    "N4L49VQuiz": [
        { "question": "use", "kanji_question": "利用します", "answer": "りようします" },
        { "question": "work (for a company)", "kanji_question": "勤めます", "answer": "つとめます" },
        { "question": "sit on (a chair)", "kanji_question": "掛けます", "answer": "かけます" },
        { "question": "spend (time), pass (time)", "kanji_question": "過ごします", "answer": "すごします" },
        { "question": "be, go, come (respectful equivalent of います, いきます, and きます)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いらっしゃいます" },
        { "question": "eat, drink (respectful equivalent of たべます and のみます)", "kanji_question": "召し上がります", "answer": "めしあがります" },
        { "question": "say, (one's name) is ~ (respectful equivalent of いいます)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おっしゃいます" },
        { "question": "do (respectful equivalent of します)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "なさいます" },
        { "question": "see, look at (respectful equivalent of みます)", "kanji_question": "ご覧になります", "answer": "ごらんになります" },
        { "question": "know (respectful equivalent of しっています)", "kanji_question": "ご存じです", "answer": "ごぞんじです" },
        { "question": "greeting, address", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "あいさつ" },
        { "question": "Japanese-style hotel or inn", "kanji_question": "旅館", "answer": "りょかん" },
        { "question": "bus stop", "kanji_question": "バス停", "answer": "バスてい" },
        { "question": "(someone else's) wife (respectful equivalent of おくさん)", "kanji_question": "奥様", "answer": "おくさま" },
        { "question": "(respectful equivalent of ～さん)", "kanji_question": "～様", "answer": "～さま" },
        { "question": "once in a while", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "たまに" },
        { "question": "anybody (respectful equivalent of だれでも)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "どなたでも" },
        { "question": "(one's name) is ~", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "～といいます" },
        { "question": "class ~ of ~th grade", "kanji_question": "～年～組", "answer": "～ねん～くみ" },
        { "question": "run (a fever)", "kanji_question": "出します", "answer": "だします" },
        { "question": "Give my best regards./Please say hello.", "kanji_question": "よろしくお伝えください。", "answer": "よろしくおつたえください。" },
        { "question": "Goodbye. (humble equivalent of しつれいします)", "kanji_question": "失礼いたします。", "answer": "しつれいいたします。" },
        { "question": "background", "kanji_question": "経歴", "answer": "けいれき" },
        { "question": "the medical department", "kanji_question": "医学部", "answer": "いがくぶ" },
        { "question": "aim for", "kanji_question": "目指します", "answer": "めざします" },
        { "question": "go on (to graduate school)", "kanji_question": "進みます", "answer": "すすみます" },
        { "question": "develop, create", "kanji_question": "開発します", "answer": "かいはつします" },
        { "question": "mouse", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "マウス" },
        { "question": "human", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ヒト" },
        { "question": "be awarded a prize", "kanji_question": "受賞します", "answer": "じゅしょうします" },
        { "question": "lecture meeting", "kanji_question": "講演会", "answer": "こうえんかい" }
    ],
    "N4L50VQuiz": [
        { "question": "go, come (humble equivalent of いきます and きます)", "kanji_question": "参ります", "answer": "まいります" },
        { "question": "be (humble equivalent of います)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "おります" },
        { "question": "eat, drink, receive (humble equivalent of たべます, のみます, and もらいます)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いただきます" },
        { "question": "say, (one's name) is ~ (humble equivalent of いいます)", "kanji_question": "申します", "answer": "もうします" },
        { "question": "do (humble equivalent of します)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いたします" },
        { "question": "see (humble equivalent of みます)", "kanji_question": "拝見します", "answer": "はいけんします" },
        { "question": "know, get to know (humble equivalent of しります)", "kanji_question": "存じます", "answer": "ぞんじます" },
        { "question": "ask, hear, visit (humble equivalent of ききます and いきます)", "kanji_question": "伺います", "answer": "うかがいます" },
        { "question": "meet (humble equivalent of あいます)", "kanji_question": "お目にかかります", "answer": "おめにかかります" },
        { "question": "make (coffee)", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "いれます" },
        { "question": "prepare", "kanji_question": "用意します", "answer": "よういします" },
        { "question": "I (humble equivalent of わたし)", "kanji_question": "私", "answer": "わたくし" },
        { "question": "guide", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ガイド" },
        { "question": "e-mail address", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "メールアドレス" },
        { "question": "schedule", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "スケジュール" },
        { "question": "the week after next", "kanji_question": "さ来週", "answer": "さらいしゅう" },
        { "question": "the month after next", "kanji_question": "さ来月", "answer": "さらいげつ" },
        { "question": "the year after next", "kanji_question": "さ来年", "answer": "さらいねん" },
        { "question": "first", "kanji_question": "初めに", "answer": "はじめに" },
        { "question": "become tense, be strained, be nervous", "kanji_question": "緊張します", "answer": "きんちょうします" },
        { "question": "prize money", "kanji_question": "賞金", "answer": "しょうきん" },
        { "question": "giraffe", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "きりん" },
        { "question": "times, days", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "ころ" },
        { "question": "(dream) be realized, come true", "kanji_question": "", "answer": "かないます" },
        { "question": "support", "kanji_question": "応援します", "answer": "おうえんします" },
        { "question": "from one's heart, sincerely", "kanji_question": "心から", "answer": "こころから" },
        { "question": "thank, be greatful", "kanji_question": "感謝します", "answer": "かんしゃします" },
        { "question": "gratitude, thanks", "kanji_question": "お礼", "answer": "おれい" },
        { "question": "How are you doing? (respectful equivalent of おげんきですか)", "kanji_question": "お元気でいらっしゃいますか。", "answer": "おげんきでいらっしゃいますか。" },
        { "question": "cause trouble, annoyance, inconvenience", "kanji_question": "迷惑をかけます", "answer": "めいわくをかけます" },
        { "question": "make good use of", "kanji_question": "生かします", "answer": "いかします" }
    ]
}